Guide to the Barrett H. Clark Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Barrett H. Clark papers
1905-1953
YCAL MSS 569
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.09
(32 boxes)
The Barrett H. Clark Papers document the work of American writer, editor, translator, and drama scholar, Barrett H. Clark, spanning the dates 1905 to 1953. The papers contain correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, and printed material providing insight into Clark's scholarship on drama. Correspondents include: Maksim Gorky, Paul Green, Eugene O'Neill, and Betty Smith.
Clark, Barrett H. (Barrett Harper), 1890-1953
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Cecile Smith Clark on the Eugene O'Neill Fund, 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Barrett Harper Clark (1890-1953)
Writer, editor, and actor, Barrett Harper Clark was born on August 26, 1890 in Toronto, Ontario, Canada to S. Henry and Anna M. Fralick Clark. Clark studied at the University of Chicago (1908-1912), spending two years in Paris, but did not complete his degree. While still a student Clark began teaching drama at Chautauqua, New York (1909-1917), an educational summer camp for adults. He also taught at Columbia University and Bryn Mawr (1928-1931).
Following graduation Clark worked as an actor and assistant stage manager in a company run by Minnie Maddern Fiske (1912-1913). Clark then worked as a literary editor for Samuel French, a company specializing in publishing drama, in New York (1918-1936). During this period Clark also served as the dramatic editor of Drama Magazine (1924-1931) and as a member of the board of directors for the Drama League America (1915-1926). When the U.S. entered WWI Clark served as the dramatic director at Camp Humphreys, Virginia, a U.S. military training camp. In 1936 Clark left Samuel French to become the executive director of the Dramatists Play Service.
In 1916 Clark married Cecile Matilda Smith, with whom he had three children: Nancy, Molly, and Barrett.
Throughout his life Clark sustained a writing career. Early in his career he translated into English a number of plays by French authors: Hervieu's The Labyrinth (1913), Three Modern Plays from the French (1914), Four Plays of the Free Theater (1914), Four Plays of Emile Augier (1915), Three Plays of Donnay (1916), Sardou's Patrie! (1915), Hyacinthe-Loyson's Apostle (1916), Curel's False Saint (1916), and Brieux's Artists' Families (1918), among others.
He wrote a number of books about drama, including: The Continental Drama of Today (1914), British and American Drama of Today (1915), Contemporary French Dramatists (1915), Study of the Modern Drama (1925), and An Hour of American Drama (1930). Clark also wrote a practical manual, How to Produce Amateur Plays (1917-25), which provided guidance for laypeople producing plays. In his chapbook, Speak the Speech (1930), Clark considers "standard English" and its impact on theatre. In Oedipus or Pollyanna (1927) Clark argues against censorship, re-visiting an issue he had earlier explored in Jurgen and the Censor (1919). Clark published an article about Eugene O'Neill in the New York Sun (May 18, 1919), and after this initial acquaintance, he went on to write a biography Eugene O'Neill (1926) and Eugene O'Neill Bibliography (with R. Sanborn) (1931). In 1928 Clark published Professor Clark, a Memoir.
Clark also edited the fifty-eight volume World's Best Plays (1915-1926) and was the first editor of America's Lost Plays (1940-1965), a twenty volume series that brought attention to obscure plays by American dramatists from the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Clark edited and co-edited a number of other works pertaining to theatre, including: Walter Prichard Eaton's Plays and Players (1916), Masterpieces of Modern Spanish Drama (1917), European Theories of the Drama (1918), Representative One Act Plays by British and Irish Authors (1921), One-Act Plays (1929), Favorite American Plays of the 19th Century (1943), and Nine Modern American Plays (1951).
Clark died on August 5, 1953 in Briarcliff, New York.
Scope and Contents
The Barrett H. Clark Papers document the work of American writer, editor, and translator, Barrett H. Clark, spanning the dates 1905 to 1953. The papers contain correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, and printed material providing insight into Clark's scholarship on drama.
Clark's intellectual circle, creative life, and work for the Samuel French company are reflected in his correspondence and writings. The Correspondence series provides insight into Clark's relationships with a number of playwrights and other authors, including Sherwood Anderson, Philip Barry, Stephen Vincent Benet, Rachel Field, Dorothy and DuBose Heyward, Sinclair Lewis, George Bernard Shaw, Upton Sinclair, Betty Smith, and Thornton Wilder. In addition, Clark's correspondence reflects his work with prominent figures in theatre, from producers and directors to actors, including Theresa Helburn, Robert Edmond Jones, Lawrence Langner, J. H. Benrimo, and William Gillette. Clark's interest in European drama is reflected in his correspondence with French and German playwrights Romain Rolland, Ernst Toller, and Fritz von Unruh. In the early 1920s Clark wrote an article about Maksim Gorki, as his correspondence with Marie Budberg, on behalf of Gorki, and related photographs illustrate.
Most notably, a number of documents trace Clark's relationship with Eugene O'Neill. In addition to his correspondence with O'Neill, the papers also include letters from O'Neill's wives Agnes Boulton O'Neill and Carlotta Monterey O'Neill. The Papers also contains Clark's drafts of his biography Eugene O'Neill, including proofs with corrections by O'Neill. The Printed Material series also includes documents relating to O'Neill, such as photographs, clippings, and pamphlets.
The Writings series is comprised of notes and drafts documenting Clark's writing as well as the writings of others. Drafts and proofs of Clark's Eugene O'Neill, memoir Professor Clark, and other works are included in the Writings series. A number of Clark's translations are also part of the Writings series, such as Jules Renard's Goodbye! and Pierre Wolff's Unhoodwinkable. Shorter publications by Clark are located in the Printed Material series. The Writings series also contains some correspondence relating to specific publications. In addition to Clark's writings the series also contains several works by Paul Green, Edgar Lee Masters, George Moore, and Lynn Riggs.
The Printed Material series contains publications on court cases (largely pertaining to copyright and plagiarism), scrapbooks of clippings and loose clippings relating to Clark and his writings, and various authors' published plays and short stories.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1905-1952. II. Writings, 1911-1953. III. Printed Material, 1915-1953.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Drama -- 19th century -- History and criticism; Drama -- 20th Century -- History and criticism; Editors -- United States; French literature -- Translations into English; Translators, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Translators -- United States -- 20th Century; Clark, Barrett H. (Barrett Harper), 1890-1953; Gorky, Maksim, 1868-1936; Green, Paul, 1894-1981; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Smith, Betty, 1896-1972; Samuel French & Son
- Correspondence, 1905-1952; Series I; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence dating from 1905 to 1952 that document the personal and professional life of Barrett H. Clark.
  - Angell, Ernest, 1927-1930 (Box 31)
    Letters concern legal case Alexander vs. Theatre Guild and Sidney Howard regarding "They Knew What They Wanted."
  - Author's League, undated (Box 1)
  - Autograph Letters, undated (Box 1)
  - Autograph Collection, undated (Box 1)
  - "A" general, 1920-1941 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, John, 1929-1939 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Maxwell, 1925-1946 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, 1926-1940 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1927-1942 (Box 1)
  - "B" general, undated (Box 1)
  - Bab, Julius, 1931-1952 (Box 1)
  - Barry, Philip, 1926-1935 (Box 1)
    With misc. leaves and typescript of a speech
  - Basshe, Em Jo, 1928-1937 (Box 1)
  - Beach, Lewis, 1932-1939 (Box 1)
  - Bein, Albert, 1931-1936 (Box 1)
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent, 1937-1941 (Box 1)
  - Benrimo, J. H., 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - Blankfort, Michael, 1936-1951 (Box 2)
  - Bordeaux, Henry, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1926-1931 (Box 2)
  - Brown, John Mason, 1926-1947 (Box 2)
  - "C" general, undated (Box 2)
  - Cabell, James Branch, 1927-1929 (Box 2)
  - Conkle, E.P., 1920-1939 (Box 2)
  - Connelly, Marc, 1930-1947 (Box 2)
  - Conrad, Joseph, 1918 May 4 (Box 2)
  - Craig, Edward Gordon, 1913-1934 (Box 2)
  - Crothers, Rachel, 1933-1944 (Box 2)
  - "D" general, undated (Box 2)
  - Day, Clarence, 1923-1934 (Box 2)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1929-1932 (Box 2)
  - Dunning, Phillip, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - De Koven, Reginald, 1913-1914 (Box 2)
  - "E" general, undated (Box 2)
  - Elser, Frank, 1929-1934 (Box 2)
  - "F" general, undated (Box 2)
  - Faragoh, F. E., 1933-1936 (Box 2)
  - Ferber, Edna, 1940-1944 (Box 2)
  - Field, Rachel, 1927-1940 (Box 2)
    With 3 sketches
  - Finch, Robert, 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - Flavin, Martin, 1925-1945 (Box 2)
    With notes and cancelled title pages
  - Franken, Rose, 1932-1934 (Box 2)
  - "G" general, undated (Box 2)
  - Galsworthy, John, 1912-1915 (Box 2)
    With signed portrait
  - Geddes, Virgil, 1928-1934 (Box 2)
  - George, W. L., 1919-1920 (Box 2)
  - Gillette, William, 1923-1936 (Box 2)
  - Glaspell, Susan, 1929-1936 (Box 2)
  - Gold, Michael, undated (Box 3)
  - Goldsmith, Clifford, 1938-1941 (Box 3)
  - Goodrich, Arthur, 1929-1936 (Box 3)
  - Gorki, Maksim, undated; 3 (Box 3)
    12 photos (1 signed by Gorki); documents signed by Louis P. Lochner; notes of an interview by Clark - all concerning Gorki
  - Gosse, Edmund William, 1911, 1913 (Box 3)
  - Green, Paul, 1925-1952; 12 (Box 3)
    With a number of letters from his wife and other family members, letters about him, and miscellaneous papers
  - "H" general, undated (Box 3)
  - Helburn, Theresa, 1921-1933 (Box 3)
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph, 1919-1928 (Box 3)
    With canceled check endorsed by him
  - Heyward, Dorothy and DuBose, 1920-1940 (Box 3)
  - Hone, Joseph M., 1935-1936 (Box 4)
  - Hopkins, Arthur, 1932-1945 (Box 4)
  - Howard, Bronson, 1905 May 13 (Box 4)
  - Howard, Sidney, 1918-1938 (Box 4)
    With 6 carbons of BHC replies and a number of letters about him
  - Hughes, Hatcher, 1929-1931 (Box 4)
  - Hughes, Rupert, 1919-1936 (Box 4)
  - Hunker, James Gibbons, 1919-1920 (Box 4)
  - "J" general, undated (Box 4)
  - Jones, Robert Edmond, 1925-1944 (Box 4)
  - "K" general, undated (Box 4)
  - Kaufman, George Simon, 1926-1946 (Box 4)
  - Kelly, George, 1925-1933 (Box 4)
  - Kemp, Harry, undated (Box 4)
  - Kummer, Clare Beecher, 1929-1936 (Box 4)
  - "L" general, undated (Box 4)
  - Langner, Lawrence, 1926-1932 (Box 4)
  - La Follette, Robert, 1908-1939 (Box 4)
  - Laverly, Emmet, 1935-1941 (Box 4)
  - Lawson, John Howard, 1925-1937 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1920-1942 (Box 4)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, 1915-1947 (Box 4)
  - Lindsay, Howard, 1939-1951 (Box 4)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1920-1933 (Box 4)
  - "M" general, undated (Box 4)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1934-1941 (Box 4)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1933-1939 (Box 4)
  - Mantle, Burns, 1925-1943 (Box 4)
  - Marquis, Don, 1914-1932 (Box 4)
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis, 1916-1942; 2 (Box 4)
  - Moore, George, 1916-1928; 2 (Box 4)
  - Morley, Christopher Darlington, 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - "N" general, undated (Box 4)
  - Nathan, George Jean, 1918-1947 (Box 4)
  - Nicholson, Kenyon, 1925-1945 (Box 4)
  - "O" general, undated (Box 5)
  - O'Higgins, Harvey, 1918-1929 (Box 5)
  - O'Neill, Agnes Boulton, 1925-1926 (Box 5)
    Concerning Eugene O'Neill
  - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey, 1931-1952 (Box 5)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1919-1944; 3 (Box 5)
    With 5 telegrams, 7 cut signatures, 3 addressed envelopes, a Christmas card, and 2 photographs
  - O'Neill, Eugene, volume with transcripts of letters sent by O'Neill to Clark, 1919-1940, undated (Box 31)
  - O'Neil, George, 1931-1937 (Box 5)
  - "P" general, undated (Box 5)
  - Peabody, Josephine Preston, 1917-1921 (Box 5)
  - Powell, Dawn, 1930-1934 (Box 5)
  - "R" general, undated (Box 5)
  - Raphaelson, Samson, 1929-1951 (Box 5)
  - Reinheimer, Howard E., 1946 (Box 31)
    Correspondence concerning legal case Columbia Pictures Corporation against Norman Krasna, Bernard Hart, and Joseph M. Hyman regarding plagiarism of "Dear Ruth." Includes correspondence with defense lawyers Irving Cohen and Lee Moselle as well as copy of Defendents' Trial Memorandum.
  - Rice, Elmer, 1917-1951 (Box 5)
    With 2 cards and a form letter
  - Richman, Arthur, 1928-1940 (Box 5)
  - Riggs, Lynn, 1927-1940 (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1916-1921 (Box 5)
  - Rolland, Romain, 1918-1926 (Box 5)
    With a number of letters about him
  - "S" general, undated (Box 6)
  - Schnitzler, Arthur, 1925-1926 (Box 6)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1910-1940 (Box 6)
  - Sherwood, Robert Emmet, 1933-1943 (Box 6)
  - Simonson, Lee, 1933-1946 (Box 6)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1924-1939 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Betty, 1937-1950; 6 (Box 6)
    With a number of reader's reports on plays, and a snapshot of her daughter
  - Spewack, Bella Cohen, 1937-1944 (Box 6)
  - Spewack, Samuel, 1937-1940 (Box 6)
  - Stringfield, Lamar, 1931 (Box 6)
  - Sundgaard, Arnold, 1937-1939 (Box 6)
  - "T" general, undated (Box 6)
  - Thomas, Albert Ellsworth, 1932-1936 (Box 6)
  - Toller, Ernst, 1923-1938 (Box 6)
  - Totheroth, Dan, 1928-1937 (Box 6)
  - Unruh, Fritz von, 1920-1944 (Box 6)
  - "W" general, undated (Box 6)
  - Wexley, John, 1931-1936 (Box 6)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1928-1938 (Box 6)
  - Williams, Jesse Lynch, 1917-1923 (Box 6)
  - Yeats, Jack B., 1931 (Box 6)
  - Young, Stanley, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Young, Stark, 1925 (Box 6)
  - "Z" general, undated (Box 6)
  - Various correspondents concerning Eugene O'Neill, 1926-1953
  - Various correspondents, 1913-1949 (Box 31)
    Contains correspondence removed from printed material.
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 11 (Box 6)
- Writings, 1911-1953; Series II; 4.8 linear feet (12 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  This series contains notes, drafts, proofs, and correspondence dating from 1911 to 1953 that document the writing career of Barrett H. Clark.
  - Arent, Arthur, 1935, mimeograph script, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent, The Devil and Daniel Webster, typescript, corrected, and proof, undated (Box 31)
  - Bennett, Clarence
    - A Noble Revenge, undated (Box 7)
      Typescript (original)
    - Uncle Sam in Cuba, undated (Box 7)
  - Clark, Barrett H.
    - America's Lost Plays, undated; 3 folders (Box 7)
      With correspondence
    - Broadway Talks Back, 1946-1947; 18 (Box 8)
      Typed and mimeographed radio scripts with publicity clippings
    - Century of Modern Drama, 1942-1946 (Box 9)
      Correspondence
    - Eugene O'Neill, 1930-1952; 3 (Box 9)
      Publication correspondence.
    - Eugene O'Neill, undated (Box 9)
      In Morocco-backed box: Original typescript. Proofs, mounted, with ms. corrections by Eugene O'Neill
    - European Theories of the Drama, 1944-1947 (Box 9)
    - Famous Fireside Plays, 1942 (Box 9)
    - Goodbye! By Jules Renard. Translated by Barrett Clark, undated (Box 9)
    - Great Plays, 1946; 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Great Plays, 1941-1942; 2 (Box 32)
    - History of the Modern Drama, 1942-1948 (Box 10)
    - Great Short Stories of the World, 1928-1949 (Box 10)
    - The Heart Has It's Reasons By Flers and Callavet, undated (Box 10)
      Carbon typescript
    - The Honest Woman, undated (Box 32)
      Play by Henri Becque translated from French into English by Clark.
    - The Hounds of Death, undated (Box 32)
      Play by Charles van Lerberghe translated from French into English by Clark.
    - Intimate Portraits, undated (Box 10)
      Clippings and correspondence
    - A Melodrama in Three Acts By H. R. Baukhage and Barrett H. Clark, 1911 (Box 10)
    - Officer 666, review, typescript, with notes and proof of "Each in His Own Way" by Rosamond Gilder, 1942 (Box 31)
    - Open letter to St. John Ervine, 1929 (Box 10)
      Envelope contains 20 ALS & TLS from various correspondents, with a number of clippings
    - Professor Clark, undated (Box 10)
    - Professor Clark, undated (Box 32)
    - Notes on Provincetown Players, undated (Box 10)
      Manuscript and typescript in volume
    - The Rivet in Grandfather's Neck, undated (Box 10)
      Typescript (carbon): Acts 2 and 3 only?
    - Theater '53, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Theatre Guild reports, 1931; 2 (Box 11)
      Manuscript and typescript (carbon). 2 notebooks
    - Unhoodwinkable By Pierre Wolff. Translated by Barrett Clark, undated (Box 11)
    - Contracts, undated; 2 (Box 11)
    - Articles, undated; 2 (Box 11)
      For the most part not published or published only in part. Typescripts (original and carbon). 1 bound volume, with 4 typescripts and a ms. laid in
    - Articles, undated (Box 32)
    - Reprints, 1935-1952 (Box 11)
    - Radio Talks, 1937-1952 (Box 32)
  - Clark, S. H.
    - Clippings, notes, letters about, letters in his estate, undated (Box 12)
  - Cornwin, Norman
    - Untitled, undated (Box 12)
      Mimeographed script
  - Elser, Frank B.
    - The Farmer Takes a Wife, 1934 (Box 12)
      Typescript (original). Written with Marc Connelly; based on Walter D. Edmonds' Rome Haul
  - Fast, Howard
    - A Place Called Freedom, undated (Box 12)
      Mimeographed script. Written with Robert Ardrey
  - Fuller, Henry B.
    - "The Coffee House" by Goldoni, undated (Box 12)
      Translator's autograph
  - Geddes, Virgil, "Laughter and the Play," "Clippings on 'The Earth Between,'" and "The Playwright's Theatre," typescripts, undated (Box 31)
  - Green, Paul
    - The Critical Year, 1939 (Box 12)
    - Day by Day, undated (Box 12)
      Mimeograph script inscribed to Barrett Clark
    - Day by Day, typescript, "Day of Reckoning," typescript, 1945 (Box 31)
    - The Hardy Plays, programmes, inscribed to Clark by Green, 1911 (Box 31)
    - The House of Connelly, 1929 (Box 12)
      Typescript (original). Inscribed to Barrett Clark. Clothbound
    - The Field God, 1929 (Box 12)
    - In Abraham's Bosom, 1927 (Box 13)
      Typescript (carbon). Inscribed to Barrett Clark. Clothbound
    - In the Valley and Other Carolina Plays, 1927; 2 (Box 13)
      Typescript (original). Inscribed to Barrett Clark. Clothbound. Gallery proofs, with ms. corrections
    - In the Valley, typescript, corrected, and proof, corrected, 1932-1936 (Box 31)
    - Lonesome Road: Six One Act Negro Plays, 1931 (Box 13)
      Typescript (carbon). Inscribed to Barrett Clark
    - Potter's Field, undated (Box 13)
      Typescript (original), with corrections. Clothbound
    - Tread the Green Grass, 1931 (Box 14)
    - White Dresses, proof,corrected, 1934 (Box 31)
  - Hughes, Glenn
    - On the Side of Angels, 1953 (Box 14)
      Mimeographed script. Inscribed to Barrett Clark
  - Hofmannsthal, Hugo von
    - Aufsatze, 1922-1923 (Box 14)
  - Masters, Edgar Lee
    - Dramatic Duologues, 1934; 3 folders (Box 14)
      Typescript (original and carbon). Incomplete; pages 39-100 only
    - New Salem, 1923 (Box 14)
      Typescript (carbon)
    - Poems of People, 1932 (Box 14)
    - Richmond, 1934 (Box 14)
      Galley and page proofs
  - Moore, George
    - Letters to Dujardin, 1886-1922 (Box 15)
      Typescript (original and carbon); clothbound
    - Correspondence, photos and clippings relating to Moore, undated (Box 15)
    - Notes on George Moore by Barrett Clark, 1922 (Box 15)
    - Further Notes on George Moore by Barrett Clark, 1922 (Box 15)
    - George Moore and His Friends by Barrett Clark, 1922 (Box 15)
    - Esther Waters by Barrett H. Clark, 1922 (Box 15)
  - O'Neill, Eugene
    - The Ancient Mariner, undated (Box 16)
      Typescript (original and 2 carbon copies)
  - Riggs, Lynn
    - Big Lake, 1928 (Box 16)
      Manuscript. Inscribed to Barrett Clark
    - The Cherokee Night, 1929; 8 folders (Box 16)
      Manuscript and typescript (original and carbon)
    - The Domino Parlor, 1930 (Box 16)
    - Green Grow the Lilacs, 1931; 2 folders (Box 16)
      Manuscript and typescript. Inscribed to Barrett Clark. Typescript (original?) with corrections
    - Knives From Syria, 1925 (Box 17)
      Typescript (original), signed
    - The Lonesome West, undated (Box 17)
    - More Sky, 1933 (Box 17)
    - Reckless, 1932 (Box 17)
      Typescript (original). Inscribed to Barrett Clark
    - Roadside, 1931-1932; 2 folders (Box 17)
      Typescript (original and carbon). Both inscribed to Barrett Clark
    - The Son of Perdition, undated (Box 17)
      Typescript (carbon); based on a novel by Cozzens
    - Correspondence concerning plays by Riggs, 1922-1932 (Box 31)
  - Rose, Sidney, Edward Harrigan and His Plays, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 32)
  - Saroyan, William
    - Afton Water, undated (Box 17)
      Typescript
  - Saul, Oscar
    - Flight by Oscar Saul and Louis Lantz, 1936 (Box 17)
  - Sheldon, Edward
    - The High Road, 1913 (Box 18)
      Typescript (original?); Mrs. Fiske's prompt copy with corrections by author, Harrison Grey Fiske, and Mrs. Fiske
  - Steinbeck, John
    - The Moon is Down, 1942; 2 folders (Box 18)
      Typescript and page proof with editorial corrections
  - Telchin, Stanley S.
    - The Group Theater, 1950 (Box 18)
      Typescript dissertation - Catholic University of America
  - Van der Veer, Ethel
    - The Six Gods, 1932 (Box 18)
      Typescript (original). Dedicated to Barrett Clark
- Printed Material, 1915-1953; Series III; 4.79 linear feet (12 boxes)
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  The series contains printed materials either by or about Barrett H. Clark, dating from 1915 to 1953. The series includes scrapbooks, clippings, pamphlets, programs and other publications. In addition the series contains clippings and photographs relating to Eugene O'Neill.
  - Printed material regarding plagiarism and copyright
    - Commonwealth v. Forever Amber, undated (Box 19)
    - Georges Lewys v. Eugene O'Neill, Boni & Liveright, Inc., Horace Liveright, Inc., and Theatre Guild, Inc., 1931 (Box 19)
      Printed material concerning alleged copyright infringement of Temple of Pallas-Athenae by Georges Lewys and Strange Interlude by Eugene O'Neill
    - Nellie Harris v. Gilbert Miller, Norman Marshall, Leslie Stokes, Sewell Stokes, Random House, Inc., and Heron Productions, Inc., 1941 (Box 19)
      Concerning Oscar Wilde: His Life and Confessions by Frank Harris
    - The People of the State of New York v. Jay Mitchell, Margaret Acquista and Jessica Norman, undated (Box 19)
      Brief of the Society of Magazine Photographers
    - Vincent McConnor v. George Kaufman, Moss Hart, George Cohan, Irving Berlin, Dennis O'Brian and Kathleen Harris as Executers of Sam H. Harris, Random House, Inc., Warner Bros. Pictures, Inc., James Monks and John Monks, 1943 (Box 19)
    - Alfred Kreymborg v. Jimmie Durante and National Broadcasting Company, Inc., 1934 (Box 19)
      Transcript of Record and Appellant's Brief
    - Esquire, Inc., v. Frank C. Walker, as Postmaster General of the United States, 1945 (Box 19)
    - Grace A. Fendler v. Oliver Morosco and Richard Walton Tully, 1926 (Box 19)
      Booklet concerning copyright infringement of His Death in Life (Fendler) appearing in In Hawaii (Tully)
    - Madge Christie v. Sam H. Harris, George S. Kaufman, Edna Ferber, Doubleday, Doran & Company, Inc., Dramatists' Play Service, Inc., 1942 (Box 19)